do you wish to be trading uh on your
deathbed
king size
um foreign
foreign
getting a little bit older you know I'm
sold now I don't look both ways when I
cross the street anymore but I'm getting
along
um little things are good actually that
like you I was fortunate to get along
these markets at the low here and uh
continue to think that the prepayers of
pessimism will be proven wrong one more
time
Larry tell us a story
well you know I had a plot today
people love to be scared
and that applied and I'm going to prove
that too they love to be scared and
especially in Market Traders love to be
scared I guess they like to get scared
out of their positions when you think
about movies
the movies that make the most monies are
the ones where you get scared where the
heads come off the bodies and people
throw up and somebody gets stabbed
people pay a lot of money to go get
scared the movies that are really happy
make you feel good they do okay but they
don't make as much money as where people
get shot up and killed and you get
scared and I think that has some
application to the market that people
just like to get scared so they listen
to all the Cassandras and all the bad
news uh instead of focusing on
the market is you've taught me and
really ingrained in me the market tends
to move higher you know I've been
trading since 1962. I think I've seen
Maybe
10 bear markets in 60 years well
obviously the odds are not real good at
having bear markets what do you think of
the market right now oh my gosh Vic
we're in a pull Market to begin with but
the the real big clicker came in this
week in my work
um I did a study in
2020 when we had the pandemic crash and
uh fortunately our indicators got us
along right at the bottom but as we
rallied back people said oh we're going
to test the lows we haven't seen the
lows yet
again the pessimist came out of the
woodwork so I did a study
going back to 1914.
and whenever we've had a bear Market
with at least two legs to the downside a
big sell-off in the market
we have never rallied back 50 percent
without the end of the bear Market in
other words once you've had a big Slam
in the market if you rally back 50
percent you can hold that for even a day
or two you're not going to retest the
low you're out you're you're game on
again you're back again and we've done
that so to me this is confirmation of
the bullishness uh that I've been
expressing uh that this is that explains
today's action to me like oh yeah after
percent rule Here We Go Happy Days Are
Here Again Vic and Larry are bullish
again how's your wife how's your wife
doing oh thank you for asking about
Louise she's doing great she's trading
and busy and uh you know she's an
investment Club I got to tell you this
Rick
she there's a bunch of ladies down here
in the Virgin lines they all tend to be
older ladies 70 and older 80s and 90s
and these women have knocked it out of
the park
way better than a mutual fund
performance and I was thinking but why
and I think I figured it out they're
they're hip they see what's going on and
they pay attention to stuff so they got
Roku early modern early Etc but they
only meet a couple times a year
so they're not in and out I think that's
one reason they're successful because
they're not quibbling about oh it was up
today it's down today what do we do
today they only meet a couple times a
year I think there's some wisdom on what
these women are doing
do you wish to be trading uh on your
Deathbed
Vic that's the real
problem I have on my life right now I
thought I could retire at 80.
and I'm finding well what do I do go
feed pigeons in the park you know that
can feed enough pigeons after a while
ago and yet because the markets are
moving today and it's really hard to
extract myself from this business
because I don't know what the heck else
to do about fishing in Montana go for a
run this morning whatever but but I I
don't know what else to do with my life
I have no life outside of the markets I
guess maybe you can really tell me how
do you approach that I bet I intend to
be trading until the end
now a few times
I've had operations and and
I've looked at the monitors showing my
respiration and hot
I always
get nervous because I think that
they're
showing the market performance rather
than
a better your body's performance
Teleperformance Victor how's your
daughter doing
she was trading as well so is she still
Trading
she's in crypto she's doing very well so
is my my son
he's an expert on crypto he's he in turn
was for Roy
and he's handling some money for us and
I he
every days
transferring before behind
getting a hundred and twenty percent
return and as a
as a various uh crypto season start
decreasing by
five percent a day so he's very
very reactive is in defying well he's
found his passion it sounds like Vic
that's great
he's going to be very
successful in life in terms of trading
he's also he's also uh he's running a
lot he's
he's actually
the best I ever did in running was seven
and a half miles seven and a half
minutes a mile
he's already
broke into five minute barrier whoa
that's very good yeah he hopes he hopes
to run home
4 20.
which is what you need you have to be a
410 to get into Harvard these days
that's a good tell
Larry what what are your favorite tells
um see markets sell off and not be able
to make new lows uh he has a lot of
uh the thing stocks and some others that
didn't make a new low in the market did
so it tells me those stocks are under
strong hands
uh since I don't Focus that much on
intraday trading I don't day trade
um you know you don't day trade you
don't try to take advantage of those no
yeah and I'll tell you why I think the
mathematics are against you because the
basis of all profits is Trend if you
don't have a trend you're not going to
make any money
so Trend as I understand trend is a
function of time the more time in a
trade the more Trend move I can get
and I want to capture Trend moves if I
can catch a big Trend move I can bet
small and catch a big move what what
made you bullish uh
seven days ago
uh a couple of things um
uh Cycles uh you know I I happen to
think Cycles can be very helpful and my
cycle forecast work was calling for a
low uh which was a published in December
about March 15th March 16th something
like that so that's that was part of it
excuse me then as we got there uh so
just you know that doesn't guarantee
that's going to happen as you get there
the way the market started to trade and
you see big big rundowns and buying came
in there's a Divergence between the way
I measure accumulation in the market
accumulation was coming into the market
but looked weak there were actually some
buyers that came in
remember that as the market Works worse
the better it is and if the the bees
make a comeback
I think it will be very bullish for
stocks and I watch it on a day-to-day
basis I see well it's very interesting
one thing I know from the work years ago
Ralph told Ralph told me in his research
showed that the most influential thing
on stock market performance the best
predictor is the deficit the larger the
deficit the more stocks rally that
number one economic indicator up to that
point and and that of in the face of a
conservative fiscal Republican like I
was back then like that flies in the
face of everything but the reality is in
the 25 years of living with that and
you've seen that as well Vic yeah
deficits or bullish why simple there's a
lot of money in circulation people have
jobs that go out and buy stuff they buy
stuff corporations make money deficits
are bullish they're not bearings us the
the hard school money school people will
tell you bye